<CHANGES>
## 2026.04.17.06
- Feat: Dashboard graph now visualises both uncompressed and compressed memory as stacked filled layers, with CPU load overlaid on top. The visible gap between the two layers is the RAM saved by ZRAM.
- Feat: Mini stats cards reworked to match the graph: Uncompressed, Compressed, Ratio, Load, Swappiness.
- Fix: Settings form POST was silently dropped on save. Refresh interval and other settings now persist correctly.
- Fix: JS/CSS cache-buster now uses filemtime so browsers pick up fresh assets on every plugin upgrade (no more manual hard-refresh after installing a new version).

## 2026.04.16.09
- Fix: Drive picker only shows mounts under /mnt/. Excludes Docker, libvirt, tmpfs, and zram-backed mounts that are unsuitable for swap files.

## 2026.04.16.08
- Major Feature: Tiered Swap Manager — ZRAM (in-memory, compressed) plus optional SSD swap file (overflow protection).
- Feature: Auto-sizes ZRAM to a percentage of system RAM (configurable 25-75%, default 50%).
- Feature: Drive picker for SSD/NVMe swap file with media detection (recommends NVMe, warns on HDD, blocks USB).
- Feature: Device labeling — all plugin-managed ZRAM devices tagged with ZRAM_CARD label.
- Feature: Device isolation — only shows plugin-owned devices; hides ZRAM from other plugins.
- Feature: Detects btrfs RAID pools and warns that swap files are not supported on multi-device btrfs.
- Feature: Handles btrfs single-device filesystems with NOCOW attribute for swap file compatibility.
- Security: CSRF token validation on all actions, escapeshellarg on all shell commands.
- Security: Swap files created with 600 permissions.
- Fix: Atomic config writes with file locking prevent corruption from concurrent requests.
- Fix: Background collector no longer reads config from USB flash every 3 seconds (cached with periodic refresh).
- Fix: History file writes are atomic (write-to-tmp then rename).
- Fix: Collector restart uses SIGTERM with SIGKILL fallback instead of sleep-and-hope.
- Architecture: Single ZRAM device model replaces multi-device (modern kernels parallelize within one device).
- Architecture: Shared config module eliminates 4x duplicated logging functions.
- Architecture: All JavaScript moved to external files for Unraid page framework compatibility.
- Upgrade: Automatic migration from legacy multi-device config to single-device on first boot.

## 2026.02.18.07
- Feature: Added ZRAM discovery to boot init log for existing devices.
- Fix: Corrected dashboard logo sizing and removed duplicate expander icon.
- Style: Finalized Unraid 7.2+ dashboard header compliance.

## 2026.02.18.04
- Feature: Standardized release labels and improved changelog preservation.
- Docs: Finalized cumulative changelog and versioning script updates.

## 2026.02.13.13
- UX: Tightened README layout for better Plugin Manager visibility.
- Fix: Resolved runaway CPU load calculation in background collector.
- Feature: Added configurable background collection interval (Default 3s).
- Feature: Implemented persistent server-side command history.
- Lifecycle: Improved plugin removal (stops collector and purges all tmp files).
- Architecture: Flattened source structure and added idempotent initialization.
- Settings: Diagnostics console now enabled by default on new installs.
- Bugfix: Resolved background collector logging issues during upgrades.
- Docs: Added comprehensive Settings and Usage guide for non-technical users.

## 2026.01.30.21
- New Feature: Persistent Dashboard History. Maintains a 1-hour rolling chart of ZRAM performance even after closing the browser.
- New Feature: Unified Diagnostics Console. Integrated tabbed console for real-time Command History and System Debug Logs.
- New Feature: In-Page Debug Viewer. Live-refreshing log viewer with truncation capabilities, bypassing external window issues.
- Improvement: Standardized Logging. Consistent [LEVEL] prefixes (INFO, DEBUG, WARN, ERROR) across all plugin components.
- Improvement: Robust Installer. Automatic configuration healing on boot to ensure stability after fresh installs or updates.
- Improvement: Performance Optimizations. Enhanced CPU Load tracking and precision for ZRAM metrics.
- Fix: Permission Stability. Standardized world-readable diagnostics logs (0666) for reliable access across web/root users.
- Fix: UI Synchronization. Resolved issues with swappiness and debug toggle states persisting across refreshes.

## 2026.01.25.66
- Official Initial Release.
</CHANGES>
