<CHANGES>
## 2026.02.13.11
- docs: Finalized cumulative changelog and versioning script updates.

## 2026.02.13.10
- UX: Tightened README layout to prevent expansion in Plugin Manager.

## 2026.02.13.09
- Fix: Resolved runaway CPU load calculation in background collector.

## 2026.02.13.08
- feat: Moved command history to backend persistent log.

## 2026.02.13.07
- fix: Purge temporary files and PID directory on plugin removal.

## 2026.02.13.06
- fix: Ensure background collector is stopped on plugin removal.

## 2026.02.13.05
- fix: Made zram_init.sh idempotent to support safe background restarts.

## 2026.02.13.04
- feat: Added background collection interval setting (default 3s).

## 2026.02.13.03
- feat: Enabled diagnostics console by default on install.

## 2026.02.13.02
- fix: Ensure collector restarts on upgrade to apply logging fix.

## 2026.02.13.01
- feat: Updated ZramCard refresh timestamp and structure flattening.

## 2026.01.30.21
- **New Feature: Persistent Dashboard History**. Maintains a 1-hour rolling chart of ZRAM performance even after closing the browser.
- **New Feature: Unified Diagnostics Console**. Integrated tabbed console for real-time Command History and System Debug Logs.
- **New Feature: In-Page Debug Viewer**. Live-refreshing log viewer with truncation capabilities, bypassing external window issues.
- **Improvement: Standardized Logging**. Consistent [LEVEL] prefixes (INFO, DEBUG, WARN, ERROR) across all plugin components.
- **Improvement: Robust Installer**. Automatic configuration healing on boot to ensure stability after fresh installs or updates.
- **Improvement: Performance Optimizations**. Enhanced CPU Load tracking and precision for ZRAM metrics.
- **Fix: Permission Stability**. Standardized world-readable diagnostics logs (0666) for reliable access across web/root users.
- **Fix: UI Synchronization**. Resolved issues with swappiness and debug toggle states persisting across refreshes.

## 2026.01.25.66
- Official Initial Release.
</CHANGES>
