<CHANGES>
## 2026.02.13.08
- **New Feature: Configurable Collection Interval**. Users can now adjust the background polling frequency (Default updated to 3s).
- **New Feature: Persistent Command History**. Terminal history is now stored on the server, ensuring consistency across tabs and sessions.
- **Improvement: Real-time Debug Logic**. Background collector now respects Debug Mode toggles immediately without requiring a restart.
- **Improvement: Robust Lifecycle Management**. Collector process now correctly restarts on upgrades and purges all temporary files upon uninstallation.
- **Improvement: Simplified Architecture**. Flattened source structure for better maintainability and faster loading.
- **Improvement: Out-of-the-box Visibility**. Diagnostics console is now enabled by default for easier troubleshooting on initial setup.
- **Fix: Idempotent Initialization**. Startup scripts now safely handle restarts, preventing duplicate device creation.

## 2026.01.30.21
- **New Feature: Persistent Dashboard History**. Maintains a 1-hour rolling chart of ZRAM performance even after closing the browser.
- **New Feature: Unified Diagnostics Console**. Integrated tabbed console for real-time Command History and System Debug Logs.
- **New Feature: In-Page Debug Viewer**. Live-refreshing log viewer with truncation capabilities, bypassing external window issues.
- **Improvement: Standardized Logging**. Consistent [LEVEL] prefixes (INFO, DEBUG, WARN, ERROR) across all plugin components.
- **Improvement: Robust Installer**. Automatic configuration healing on boot to ensure stability after fresh installs or updates.
- **Improvement: Performance Optimizations**. Enhanced CPU Load tracking and precision for ZRAM metrics.
- **Fix: Permission Stability**. Standardized world-readable diagnostics logs (0666) for reliable access across web/root users.
- **Fix: UI Synchronization**. Resolved issues with swappiness and debug toggle states persisting across refreshes.

## 2026.01.25.66
- Official Initial Release.
</CHANGES>
